The nation's heart was touched by...
Gods and Generals is a drama, history, war film directed by Ronald F. Maxwell.
The film centers mostly around the personal and professional life of Thomas "Stonewall" Jackson, a brilliant if
eccentric Confederate general, from the outbreak of the American Civil War until its halfway point.
Lt. Gen. Thomas Stonewall Jackson, played by Stephen Lang.
Lt. Col. Joshua Lawrence Chamberlain, played by Jeff Daniels.
Gen. Robert E. Lee, played by Robert Duvall.
Sgt. Buster Kilrain, played by Kevin Conway.
Sgt. Thomas Chamberlain, played by C. Thomas Howell.
Capt. Alexander 'Sandie' Pendleton, played by Jeremy London.
Gods and Generals is a 2003 American epic war drama
film written and directed by Ronald F.
It is adapted from the 1996 novel by Jeffrey Shaara and
prequel to Maxwell's 1993 film Gettysburg.
The film follows the story of Confederate general Stonewall Jackson from the beginning of
the American Civil War to his death at the Battle of Chancellorsville.
It stars Stephen Lang as Jackson, Jeff Daniels as Lieutenant Colonel
Joshua Chamberlain and Robert Duvall as General Robert E.
The cast also features Mira Sorvino, Kevin Conway, C.
Thomas Howell and Frankie Faison.
Most of the film was personally financed by media mogul Ted Turner.
Originally running over five hours in length, the film was cut by an hour and a half for its 2003 theatrical
release, with the full "Extended Director's Cut" being released eight years later in 2011.
The film was both a critical and commercial failure.
Although film critics complimented its performances and historically accurate details
such as costumes, they criticized its length, pacing, and screenplay.
The film was also heavily criticized by both critics and
historians for its "pro-Confederate slant".
The Southern Poverty Law Center, as well as numerous writers and historians,
pointed out that the film endorsed the "Lost Cause" myth.
Both Shaara and Maxwell expressed displeasure at the theatrical edition of the film, and its poor returns forced
Turner to cancel Maxwell's planned adaptation of Shaara's final Civil War novel The Last Full Measure.
The film explores themes of general, based on true
story, rise and fall, battle, death.
The tone is emotional.